Guide to the Henry Horenstein photographs, 1970-2013 RL.11564
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Racing Days, 1975-1994; 1.5 Linear Feet 3 boxes 31 prints
  - Jockeys waiting, Fair Grounds, 1977; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0054)
    Marks: 147-20.
  - Steam room, Fair Grounds, 1977; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0055)
    Marks: 146-21A.
  - Steve Cauthen, Saratoga Race Course, Saratoga, New York, 1977; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0018)
  - Urine collector, Fair Grounds, 1977; 23 x 16 1/2 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0056)
    Edition: 2 of 3. Marks: 129-30.
  - Cooling off, Saratoga Race Course, 1978; 11 x 14 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0057)
    Marks: 271-12A.
  - Dead horse, Great Barrington Fair, 1978; 14 x 11 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0058)
    Marks: 313-34.
  - Groom, Great Barrington Fair, 1978; 8 x 10 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 6, Image RL.11564-P-0059)
    Marks: Photographer's stamp.
  - Horse, groom, blacksmith, Saratoga Race Course, 1978; 10 x 8 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 6, Image RL.11564-P-0060)
    Edition: 2 of 3. Marks: 274-22; 82.
  - Maryland George, Northampton Fair, Northampton, Massachusetts, 1978; 23 x 16 1/4 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0061)
  - Maryland George, Northampton Fair, Northampton, Massachusetts, 1978; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0017)
    Marks: 772-11 / 1 of 4
  - Shoeshine stand, Saratoga Race Course, 1978; 16 1/2 x 23 1/4 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0062)
    Edition: 4 of 4. Marks: 263-31.
  - Yearling sale, Saratoga Race Course, 1979; 10 x 8 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 6, Image RL.11564-P-0063)
    Edition: 3 of 3. Marks: 488-15; 24; 33; LN 2.
  - Finish line, Oaklawn Park, 1981; 14 x 11 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0064)
    Marks: 531-22A.
  - After the finish, Keeneland, 1985; 11 x 14 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0065)
    Marks: 854-22.
  - After the weigh-in, Laurel Race Course, 1985; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0066)
  - Bettors resting, Keeneland, 1985; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0067)
  - Groom applying bandages, Saratoga Race Course, 1985; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0068)
    Marks: 85-838(3A); 6 (circled); AMC 5/11
  - Identifier, Northampton Fair, 1985; 16 1/2 x 23 7/8 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0069)
    Edition: 2 of 3. Marks: 770-3A.
  - Jockey's excuse, 1985; 19 7/8 x 23 7/8 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0070)
  - Resting between races, Northampton Fair, 1985; 16 x 20 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 3, Image RL.11564-P-0071)
  - Valet, jockeys, trainers, Keeneland, 1985; 10 x 8 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 6, Image RL.11564-P-0072)
    Marks: 882-30, #49.
  - Betting line, Santa Anita, 1986; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0073)
  - Last fence, Fair Hill, 1986; 11 x 14 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0074)
    Marks: 1484-4A.
  - Punter, Santa Anita, 1986; 10 x 8 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 6, Image RL.11564-P-0075)
    Unsigned.
  - Stretch drive, Santa Anita Park, 1986; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0076)
    Edition: 4 of 5. Marks: 1067-13.
  - Top of the stretch, Suffolk Downs, 1986; 11 x 14 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0077)
    Marks: 1240-18.
  - Uncashed tickets, Santa Anita Park, 1986; 16 1/2 x 23 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 4, Image RL.11564-P-0078)
    Edition: 4 of 5. Marks: 1079-14.
  - From paddock to post, Hippdrome Saint-Cloud, 1994; 11 x 14 inches, gelatin silver print (Box 5, Image RL.11564-P-0079)
    Marks: 94-160-30.
  - Joey Rusham, late 1970s?; 8 x 10 inches, Gelatin silver print (Box 6, Image RL.11564-P-0080)
- Shoot What You Love, 2013
  Title of this series refers to advice Horenstein received from a photography mentor; it is also the title of Horenstein's 2016 visual memoir, Shoot What You Love: Tips and Tales From a Working Photographer in which many of the images of this collection appear.
  - Photographer, Carol's Pub, Chicago, Illinois, 2013; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Chromogenic print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0019)
- Show, 2006-2011; 5 prints
  Prints belong to a documentary project in which Horenstein photographed cabaret and drag performers in Los Angeles, New York City, and other places. All four images in this series were published in the photobook Show, and two in Shoot What You Love.
  - Jackie Beat, California Institute of Abnormalarts, Los Angeles, California, 2007; 25 x 17 inches; Pigment print (Box 2, Image RL.11564-P-0020)
    Marks: 3/15 AC print '09
  - Flambeaux, New York, New York, 2006; 17 1/8 x 25 inches; Pigment print (Box 2, Image RL.11564-P-0021)
    Marks: 2/15
  - Prince Poppycock, Los Angeles, California, 2006; 24 7/8 x 17 inches; Pigment print (Box 2, Image RL.11564-P-0022)
    Marks: 4/15 AC '09
  - The Slipper Room, New York, New York, 2008; 24 7/8 x 17 inches; Pigment print (Box 2, Image RL.11564-P-0023)
    Marks: 2/15 AC print Feb 2012
  - Slow dancing, El Mani Club, Caracas, Venezuela, 2011; 16 x 19 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0024)
- Wesorts, 1997-2006; .5 Linear Feet 32 prints 8x10 inches
  These 32 black-and-white photographs were taken from 1997 to 2003 by Henry Horestein as part of a project to document a cluster of unique communities in central Maryland in which the majority of inhabitants are of mixed race, frequently tri-racial. The name of the series and project comes from a phrase, "we sorts," used by locals to refer to themselves and to their community.
  Subjects include individual men and women, as well as family groups, at home, in yards, at a church and cemetery, and in a bar. One portrait takes in three generations of the Proctor family. Locations in Maryland include Bel Alton, Port Tobacco, and Hillcrest Heights. A few of the portraits are of former inhabitants of these small communities now living in Washington, D.C.
  The gelatin silver prints measure approximately 8x10 inches, and were printed in 1997, 2003, and 2008.
  - Window, Wheeler's Barbershop, Marbury, Maryland, 2006; 19 7/8 x 15 7/8 inches; Gelatin silver print (Box 1, Image RL.11564-P-0025)
    Marks: #4 06-169 (5)
  - Ruth Harley Robinson at her home in NE Washington, DC ("her crack on the crack"), 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0121)
    Marks: 03-246 #1
  - Ruth Harley Robinson and William "Sonny" Robinson in front of the big screen TV in their home in NE Washington, DC, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0122)
    Marks: 03-252 #11
  - Catherine "Catty" Proctor Thomas, at home in SE Washington, DC, holding a portrait of her family, including husband Bernard Thomas, daughter Bernadette Thomas and son Craig Thomas, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0123)
    Marks: 03-254 #8
  - Neighbor of Aunt Lonie's in Bel Alton, Maryland, 2003; 7 1/4 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0124)
    Marks: 03-261 #11
  - Three generations from left: Elise Proctor (wife of Martin "Baker" Proctor), Robin Tucker Forrest, Carolyn Tucker, Thelma Proctor Scott, Bernadette Thomas Briscoe, Ruth Harley Robinson, Baker Proctor, Catherine "Catty" Proctor Thomas and squatting, Ruth's granddaughter April Coleman, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0125)
    Marks: 03-265 #9
  - Interior, Proctor's Inn, Port Tobacco, Maryland, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0126)
    Marks: 03-274 #9
  - Olivia Chase's house (Aunt Lonie's neighbor who she could see from her front window across Rt 301), Bel Alton, Maryland, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0127)
    Marks: 03-277 #3
  - Mary Lonie Proctor Butler, the youngest of Ned Proctor's 16 children, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0128)
    Marks: 03-279 #2
  - Pool hall, Hillcrest Heights, Maryland, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0129)
    Marks: 03-282 #3
  - Third daughter Carolyn Tucker and her mother Thelma Scott, 2003; 7 1/4 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0130)
    Marks: 03-290 #7
  - Thelma Proctor Scott, 2003; 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0131)
    Marks: 03-290 #11
  - William "Sonny" Robinson, 2003; 7 1/4 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0132)
    Marks: 03-291 #1
  - Aunt Lonie, Mary Lonie Butler, 2003; 7 1/4 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0133)
    Marks: 03-292 #2
  - Aunt Lonie Butler at St. Ignatius Catholic Church, 1997; 7 3/8 x 8 7/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0134)
    Marks: 97-177
  - Lester Proctor, owner and proprietor of Proctor's Inn, Waldorf, Maryland, 1997; 8 3/8 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0135)
    Marks: 97-181
  - Leonard Almstead Scott and Thelma Scott at their home in Hillcrest Heights, Maryland, 1998; 8 7/8 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0136)
    Marks: 97-183
  - Vincent's nephew Little Tony, Vinetia on Robin's lap, Skye, Vincent palming Vinetia's head, and Little Vincent (left to right), 1998; 8 7/8 x 7 1/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0137)
    Marks: 97-193
  - Aunt Lonie, in the cemetery at St. Ignatius Church, Chapel Point, Charles County, Maryland, 1997; 7 3/4 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0138)
    Marks: 97-194
  - Aunt Lonie, walking in the cemetery at St. Ignatius. The Port Tobacco River flows from the right to the Potomac River at far left, 1997; 7 1/4 x 8 3/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0139)
  - Aunt Lonie's only child: Earl Butler, at his childhood home in Bel Alton, Maryland, 1998; 8 7/8 x 7 1/4 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0140)
    Marks: 97-195
  - Mr. Scott in the backyard in Hillcrest Heights, Maryland ("Once in a blue moon" prints work with seersucker stripes), 1998; 7 3/8 x 8 7/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0141)
    Marks: 97-198
  - Mr. Scott's only son, Michael Renaldo Proctor, in one of his own designs, 1998; 7 3/8 x 8 7/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0142)
    Marks: 97-199
  - Leonard Almstead Scott, 1998; 7 1/4 x 8 7/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0143)
  - Father and son, Mr. Scott and Michael, in the backyard in Hillcrest Heights, Maryland, 1998; 7 3/8 x 8 7/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0144)
    Marks: 97-199. Michael's middle name Renaldo is an anagram of his father's first name Leonard.
  - Aunt Lonie on the screened porch of her home in Bel Alton, Maryland, 1998; 7 1/4 x 8 7/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0145)
    Marks: 97-203
  - Dancers at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 6 3/8 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0146)
    Marks: 97-204-5
  - Doing the bump at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 6 1/2 x 9 5/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0147)
    Marks: 97-204 #10
  - Taking a break at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 6 3/8 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0148)
    Marks: 97-205-10A
  - On the dance floor at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 6 3/8 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0149)
    Marks: 97-205-14A
  - Worshipping the disco ball at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 6 3/8 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0150)
    Marks: 97-205-16A
  - A woman with two dancing partners at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 6 3/8 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0151)
    Marks: 97-205-33A
  - Chilling at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 9 3/8 x 6 3/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0152)
    Marks: 97-206-15
  - Both hands full at Proctor's Inn, 1997 August; 6 3/8 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 9, Image RL.11564-P-0153)
    Marks: 97-206-35